A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Officers' Diaries xFA118
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Stevens, David H.
  - Index, 1943 (Reel M Ste 2, Frame 746, Box 445)
    1943 Index; 4 pages arranged by interview.
    Encyclopedias and dictionaries; East Asia; Latin America; United States; Language and languages; Libraries; Humanities; Linguistics; Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1943 (Reel M Ste 2, Frame 750, Box 445)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on the war effort, Latin American and Far East studies, and contemporary life and culture. Included in the diary is a pamphlet titled, "The United Nations Series."
    United States; Libraries; Language and languages; Linguistics; Humanities; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; East Asia; Latin America; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Stevens, David Harrison
  - 1944 (Reel M Ste 2, Frame 958, Box 445)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on the war effort, Latin American and Far East studies, and contemporary life and culture.
    Education; Humanities; Bibliography; United States; Libraries; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; East Asia; Language and languages; Linguistics; Anthropology; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Stevens, David Harrison
  - 1945 (Reel M Ste 3, Frame 1, Box 446)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on the war effort, Latin American and Far East studies, and contemporary life and culture. Stevens takes a trip to Mexico to survey the Rockefeller Foundation Humanities program in Mexico. The diary includes a list of post war fellowships as well.
    Libraries; Drama; Humanities; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Language and languages; Economics; Latin America; Linguistics; Mexico; Philosophy and religion; United States; Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1946 (Box 446, Reel M Ste 3, Frame 227)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on language and foreign culture, American studies, and libraries and museums. Stevens tours British universities to determine prospects in Slavic, Near Eastern and Far Near Eastern studies, and effects of World War II on the Press. The diary includes "Mr. David H. Stevens' Calendar of British Visits September 27th- October 26, 1946."
    Linguistics; Language and languages; World War II; Cataloging; England; United States; Humanities; East Asia; Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1947 (Box 446, Reel M Ste 3, Frame 434)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio.
    East Asia; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Education; United States; Drama; Humanities; Libraries; Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1948 January-June (Reel M Ste 3, Frame 638, Box 446)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio. The diary includes a calendar/itinerary for trip to Mexico from January 22-31, 1948.
    Mexico; Humanities; Theater; Translations; Libraries; Drama; United States; Guatemala; Language and languages; Linguistics; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Stevens, David Harrison
  - 1948 July-December (Reel M Ste 3, Frame 754, Box 446)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio. Includes Diaries on Great Britain July 1948.
    Language and languages; Humanities; Africa; East Asia; Ireland; United States; England; Microfilms; Music; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Linguistics; Translations; Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1949 January-April (Reel M Ste 3, Frame 890, Box 446)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio. Stevens tours universities and libraries to survey Rockefeller Foundation Humanities grants. The diary includes notes on Stevens' visit to Europe from April 18 to June 12, 1949.
    Europe; Canada; United States; Education; Radio; Motion pictures; Humanities; Drama; East Asia; Microfilms; Austria; England; Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1949 May-December (Reel M Ste 3, Frame 1,023, Box 446)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio. Relations with China are documented. The diary includes notes on Stevens' visit to Europe from April 18 to June 12, 1949.
    History; Language and languages; Linguistics; Humanities; China; Germany; Scotland; England; Ireland; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Stevens, David Harrison
- Stewart, Jane A.
  - 1962-1963 June (Box 447)
  - 1963 July-1964 May (Box 447)
  - 1964 June-1966 (Box 447)
- Stewart, John B.
  - 1953-1954 (Box 447)
  - 1955 (Box 447)
- Strode, George K.
  - 1927 (Box 448, Box 452, Reel M Str 1, Frame 1)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division who receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members. The dairy documents a sewage experimental station, a visit to Croatia to survey the opening of a school of public health and to examine local public health as well as updates from IHD fellows.
    Public health; Spain; Italy; Switzerland; Plague; Communicable diseases; Sanitation; Hygiene; Cholera; Tuberculosis; Europe; United States; Croatia; France; Venereal diseases; Malaria; Epidemiology; Smallpox; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1928 January-June (Reel M Str 1, Frame 105, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division who receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members. He interviews professionals in the field of public. The diary documents field studies in malaria, impressions of Belgium Colonial Health Services, contains Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division plans for 1928. Strode also travels to Germany and visits. The progress of IHD fellows is documented as well.
    Communicable diseases; Venereal diseases; Tropical medicine; Sanitation; Infant -- Mortality; Europe; Public health; Germany; Austria; Nursing; Tuberculosis; Malaria; Hygiene; Poland; Bulgaria; France; Belgium; England; Ireland; Netherlands; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K.
  - 1928 July-December (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 258)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division who receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members. The dairy documents updates from IHD fellows and as well describes current year program initiatives.
    Denmark; Norway; France; Malaria; Hookworm disease; Nursing; Typhoid fever; Europe; Germany; Serbia; Spain; Hygiene; Public health; Sanitation; Tuberculosis; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K.
  - Index, 1929 (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 376)
    10 pages
    Tuberculosis; Communicable diseases; Ireland; Sanitation; Yugoslavia; Italy; Morocco; Lithuania; Venereal diseases; Hygiene; France; Sweden; Spain; South America; Romania; Portugal; Poland; Norway; Czechoslovakia; Denmark; England; Finland; Germany; Greece; Hungary; India; Public health; Nursing; China; Chile; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1929 (Reel M Str 1, Frame 386, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division who receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members. He interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary surveys Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division programs in Europe. Strode also received IHD fellows updates.
    Sweden; France; India; Hungary; Greece; Germany; Finland; England; Lithuania; Morocco; Norway; Poland; Portugal; Romania; South America; Spain; Czechoslovakia; Denmark; Chile; China; Nursing; Public health; Tuberculosis; Communicable diseases; Venereal diseases; Hygiene; Yugoslavia; Italy; Ireland; Sanitation; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K.
  - Index, 1930 (Reel M Str 1, Frame 567, Box 448)
    12 pages.
    Public health; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K.
  - 1930 (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 579)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes IHD interests in Ireland, surveys Turkey’s public health programs and various updates on public health nursing projects.
    Yugoslavia; Norway; Austria; Romania; Czechoslovakia; Bulgaria; Turkey; Public health; Spain; Switzerland; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Greece; Italy; Hungary; England; Denmark; Germany; France; Venereal diseases; Nursing; Tuberculosis; Hygiene; Yellow fever; Sanitation; Malaria; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K.
  - Index, 1931 (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 702)
    Public health; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1931 (Reel M Str 1, Frame 721, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes International Health Division public health program activities in Poland, Denmark and Romania.
    Sanitation; Public health; Holland (Netherlands: Province); United States; Hygiene; Tuberculosis; Nursing; Greece; Poland; England; Finland; Hungary; Austria; Switzerland; Romania; Norway; Denmark; France; Bulgaria; Czechoslovakia; Germany; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1932 (Reel M Str 1, Frame 889, Box 448)
    6 pages.
  - 1932 (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 895)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes a visit to Spain to discuss Rockefeller Foundation programs, a field research survey of malaria in Greece, a maternal mortality study in Germany and a survey of public health services in Portugal.
    Poland; Belgium; Switzerland; Austria; Czechoslovakia; Romania; Germany; England; Portugal; Hungary; Greece; Spain; France; Latvia; Public health; Tuberculosis; Sanitation; Malaria; Mothers -- Mortality; Hygiene; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K.
  - Index, 1933 (Reel M Str 2, Frame 1, Box 448)
    6 pages
  - 1933 (Reel M Str 2, Frame 15, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on malaria field research in Greece and Bulgaria.
    Romania; Austria; Denmark; Switzerland; Netherlands; Germany; France; England; Public health; Infant -- Mortality; Spain; Hygiene; Malaria; Sanitation; Tuberculosis; Industrial hygiene; Nursing; Bulgaria; Albania; Greece; Italy; Croatia; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1934 (Reel M Str 2, Frame 140, Box 448)
    20 pages.
  - 1934 (Reel M Str 2, Frame 160, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on malaria in Spain and Portugal and an infant mortality study.
    Hungary; Italy; Bulgaria; Romania; France; Yugoslavia; Austria; Portugal; England; Denmark; Germany; Switzerland; Spain; Greece; Turkey; Public health; Malaria; Hygiene; Industrial hygiene; Nursing; Tuberculosis; Sanitation; Medicine, Preventive; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K.
  - Index, 1935 (Reel M Str 2, Frame 339, Box 448)
    17 pages.
  - 1935 (Reel M Str 2, Frame 356, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The International Health Division carried out projects in malaria control, supported public health programs, gave aid to the organization or maintenance of essential services of state and national health departments and continued its contribution to the training of public health personnel as well as supports a fellowship program.
    Portugal; Spain; Germany; Poland; Greece; Palestine; Egypt; Italy; Switzerland; Romania; Hungary; Denmark; Czechoslovakia; Austria; England; France; Sanitation; Nutrition; Yugoslavia; Hookworm disease; Malaria; Hygiene; Nursing; Public health; Turkey; Lebanon; Cyprus; Sweden; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1936 (Reel M Str 2, Frame 528, Box 449)
    14 pages.
  - 1936 (Reel M Str 2, Frame 542, Box 449)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on the scarlet fever project in Romania, a malaria study in Portugal and various surveys of public health programs in Europe.
    Scarlatina; Public health; Romania; Nursing; Hygiene; Austria; Greece; Hungary; France; England; Portugal; Italy; Albania; Bulgaria; Turkey; Czechoslovakia; Poland; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1937 (Box 449, Reel M Str 2, Frame 698)
    13 pages.
  - 1937 (Box 449, Reel M Str 2, Frame 711)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is the control and investigation of specific diseases and to aid state and local health services. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on yellow fever field studies in Africa and malaria research in Italy.
    Sudan; Uganda; Kenya; India; Sweden; Denmark; Serbia; Bulgaria; Cyprus; Italy; Czechoslovakia; Romania; Hygiene; Public health; Africa; Palestine; France; Nursing; Malaria; Yellow fever; Egypt; Greece; Belgium; England; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K.
  - Index, January 1-June 24, 1938 (Box 449, Reel M Str 2, Frame 890)
  - Index, June 25-December 31, 1938 (Box 449, Reel M Str 2, Frame 904)
    7 pages.
  - 1938 (Box 449, Reel M Str 2, Frame 911)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is the control and investigation of specific diseases and to aid state and local health services. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes impressions of public health in East Asia and India, and information on yellow fever in Africa.
    Uganda; Sudan; England; Switzerland; France; Denmark; Sweden; Romania; Hungary; Singapore; Java; Philippines; Hong Kong; India; Egypt; Medical education; Yellow fever; Sanitation; Nursing; Epidemiology; Communicable diseases; Cholera; Tropical medicine; Malaria; Hygiene; Cyprus; Public health; Japan; Hawaii; Fiji; American Samoa; United States; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1939 (Box 449, Reel M Str 3, Frame 1)
  - 1939 (Box 449, Reel M Str 3, Frame 16)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division working at the New York Office. The focus of the International Health Division is the control and investigation of specific diseases and to aid state and local health services. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on IHD program work in the Far East, fellowships and observations of Gambiae project in Brazil.
    Epidemiology; Tuberculosis; Yellow fever; Medical education; Hygiene; Entomology; Sanitation; Malaria; United States; Brazil; Public health; Anopheles gambiae; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1940 (Reel M Str 3, Frame 226, Box 449)
  - 1940 January 1-June 26 (Reel M Str 3, Frame 243, Box 449)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division working at the New York Office. The International Health Division assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. The IHD has withdrawn many of its European programs due to World War II and focuses its effort in South America specifically for malaria field studies. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health.
    Industrial hygiene; Malaria; Argentina; Brazil; Chile; Uruguay; Ecuador; Peru; Dispensaries; Infant -- Mortality; Medical education; Tuberculosis; United States; Yellow fever; Panama; Venezuela; Public health; Epidemiology; Hygiene; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1940 June 27-December 31 (Reel M Str 3, Frame 364, Box 449)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division working at the New York Office. The International Health Division assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. The IHD has withdrawn many of its European programs due to World War II and focuses its effort in South America specifically for malaria field studies. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary contains information on a nursing school project in Madrid and Strode’s travels in Portugal, Spain and France.
    Tuberculosis; Refugees; Nutrition; Hygiene; World War II; Public health; Spain; France; United States; Portugal; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1941 (Reel M Str 3, Frame 526, Box 450)
    18 pages.
  - 1941 (Reel M Str 3, Frame 544, Box 450)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division working at Paris Office. The International Health Division assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary focuses on immediate wartime activities such as aiding public health services in Lisbon, Madrid and Marseilles. Strode travels to Russia to survey medical education and services, and focuses on nutrition programs.
    Spain; Portugal; France; Public health; Hygiene; Medical education; Nursing; Nutrition; Sanitation; World War II; Wake Island; Hawaii; Switzerland; United States; Scotland; England; Russia; India; Singapore; Australia; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1942 May 28-December 31 (Reel M Str 3, Frame 766, Box 450)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. The IHD focuses on health phases of the war effort, nutrition studies, research on various vaccines and field studies. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary details Latin American programs and a public health survey of northern Africa.
    Nutrition; Vaccines; Yellow fever; Tropical medicine; Nursing; Hygiene; Public health; Louse; Ghana; Algeria; Puerto Rico; Brazil; World War II; United States; Medical literature; Insect baits and repellents; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; American Red Cross
  - Index, 1942 (Reel M Str 3, Frame 911, Box 450)
    29 pages.
  - 1942 January 1-May 27 (Reel M Str 3, Frame 941, Box 450)